Akorede Olawole

I am a proactive, smart-driven engineer and leader with 2 years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient Python developer. I have built software that solves real-life problems including RecyclyPay solution and Dispatch webApp.

10 Bola Ige Oke-Ado Ibadan.

Number: +2348102528777

Email:akoredeolawole@gmail.com

Github:https://github.com/Mbbluestalker
Linkedin:https://www.linkedin.com/in/ako
rede-olawole-652900a7/

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Lagos — Software Engineer

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2022

- A member of a team that developed a Recycling Solution for RecyclePay project, Dispatch Buddy.
- Built projects with Django(DRF), React.js, Python, and Javascript.
- Handled Database Management Systems with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Experience writing units and integration tests.
- Exposure to agile methodologies

International Data Management Systems, Lagos — *IT instructor / IT support*

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2022

- Planning lessons and activities that facilitate students' acquisition of basic and advanced computer skills.
- Instructing in a manner that develops students' confidence in their abilities.
- Observing and managing classroom dynamics.
- Downloading important software updates and maintaining hardware.
- Tracking and communicating students' advancement throughout the course.

Bincom(Social Lender), Ibadan — Project Assistant

JULY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Work collaboratively with the project manager and team to maximize productivity
- Collaborate with the whole project team, contributing to the entire project lifecycle
- Organize and monitor schedules and see that deadlines are met
- Coordinate efforts within the team and with outside consultants efficiently
- Report updates verbally and in written form to management
- Monitor budget and help ensure resources are used efficiently
- Help discern requirements and assign tasks to team members
- Demonstrate commitment to clients' needs and confidentiality continuously
- Exposure to agile methodologies

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap
- JavascriptPython
- Django
- Django Rest Framework (API)
- React JS
- Scrum
- CI/CD
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Jira
- REST API
- Version Control with Git and GitHub.
- Test-Driven Development.

PROJECTS

DISPATCH-BUDDY:

Dispatch buddy is an online delivery service solution that connects users to dispatch riders available to move goods from one location to another.

Technologies Used - React and NodeJS.

Link: https://dispatch-buddy.netlify.app/

KENISCE GROUP:

Kenisce Group is interested in reducing communication issues associated with client-developer relationships prevalent today, by providing access to quality web development, and design services.

Technologies Used: Built with REACT and Django FrontEnd Link: https://kenisceroyal.netlify.app/
BackEnd Link: https://blog.kenisceroyal.com/

GitHub-FINDER:

A finder App where users can do a quick search for GitHub profiles. Built with REACT and GitHub API.

Technologies Used - React and GitHub API.

Link: https://gitfinder-context.netlify.app/

RECYCLE PAY:

A simple blog site.

Technologies Used: Python3 (Django, Django Rest Framework),

Javascript, Tailwind, SQLite, PostgreSQL.

Link: https://recycle-pay.herokuapp.com/api/v1/auth/register/

SUPREME KITCHEN:

A food restaurant app. Built with REACT

Link: https://supremekitchen.netlify.app

EDUCATION

Tai Solarin University — B.sc

OCTOBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2015

Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science From Tai Solarin University, Nigeria.

Decagon Institute — Software Engineering

JANUARY 2020 - JUNE 2020